You are the last man
whom I could ever marry!
Do you think any consideration would
tempt me? Your arrogance, your conceit,
and your selfish disdain
for the feelings of others!
My opinion of you was decided when I heard
Mr. Wickham's story of your dealings with him.
Well at least in that I may defend myself.
Could you expect me to rejoice
in the inferiority of your connections?
To congratulate myself on the hope of relations
whose condition in life is so below my own?
You are mistaken, Mr. Darcy.
Your declaration merely spared me
the concern I might have felt in refusing you,
had you behaved in a more
gentleman-like manner.
Who's there, Fitzwilliam?
- Darcy! We'd quite despaired of you!
- Is that my nephew?
Where have you been?
Let him come in and explain himself!
No. You will forgive me.
- You'll forgive me.
- Darcy, you are unwell?
I'm very well, thank you, but I have a pressing
matter of business. You'll forgive me.
Make my apologies to Lady Catherine, Fitzwilliam.
To Miss Elizabeth Bennet.
Be not alarmed, madam, on receiving this letter,
that it contain any repetition
of those sentiments or offers
which were this evening so disgusting to you.
But I must be allowed to defend myself
against the charges laid at my door.
In particular those relating to Mr. Wickham,
which if true, would indeed be grievous,
but are wholly without foundation,
and which I can only refute by laying before you
his connection with my family.
Mr. Wickham is the son of a very respectable
man, who had the management of our estates.
My own father was fond of him
and held him in high esteem.
We played together as boys.
After his father's early death, my father
supported him at school and at Cambridge,
and hoped he would make the church
his profession.
But by then George Wickham's habits were
as dissolute as his manners were engaging.
My own excellent father died five years ago.
His attachment to Mr. Wickham
was to the last so steady,
that he desired that a valuable family living
might be his as soon as it was vacant.
Mr. Wickham declined
any interest in the church as a career,
but requested, and was granted,
the sum of 3,000 pounds instead of the living.
He expressed an intention of studying the law.
I wished, rather than believed him to be sincere.
Thank you.
I'm most exceedingly obliged.
All connection between us
seemed now dissolved.
Georgiana.
Being now free from all restraint,
his life was one of idleness and dissipation.
How he lived, I know not.
But last summer our paths crossed again,
under the most painful circumstances,
which I myself would wish to forget.
My sister, Georgiana,
who is more than ten years my junior,
was left to the guardianship
of Colonel Fitzwilliam and myself.
About a year ago,
she was taken from school to Ramsgate,
and placed in the care of a Mrs. Younge, in whose
character we were most unhappily deceived.
And thither also went Mr. Wickham,
undoubtedly by design.
She was persuaded to believe herself in love,
and to consent to an elopement.
She was then but fifteen years old.
A day or two before the intended elopement,
I joined them unexpectedly.
Unable to support the idea of grieving a brother
whom she looked up to almost as a father,
she acknowledged the whole plan to me
at once.
You may imagine what I felt and how I acted.
Mr. Wickham left the place immediately.
Come.
Mr. Wickham relinquished his object, which was
of course, my sister's fortune of 30,000 pounds.
A secondary motive must have been
to revenge himself on me.
Had he succeeded, his revenge
would have been complete indeed.
This, madam, is a faithful narrative
of all my dealings with Mr. Wickham.
You do look pale, Lizzy.
Why don't you have some breakfast?
- I'm sure it will do you good.
- I am well, Charlotte.
I've stayed indoors too long.
Fresh air and exercise is all I need.
The woods around Rosings are so beautiful
at this time of year.
Miss Bennet!
Mr. Darcy.
I've been walking the grove some time
in the hope of meeting you.
Will you do me the honor of reading this letter'?
This, madam, is a faithful narrative
of my dealings with Mr. Wickham,
and for its truth I can appeal
to the testimony of Colonel Fitzwilliam,
who knows every particular of these transactions.
I know not under what form of falsehood
Mr. Wickham imposed himself on you,
but I hope you'll acquit me
of cruelty towards him.
I found that I'd better not meet Mr. Darcy.
Scenes might arise,
unpleasant to more than myself.
The other charge leveled at me, is that
regardless of the sentiments of either party,
I detached Mr. Bingley from your sister.
I have no wish to deny this, nor can I blame
myself for any of my actions in this matter.
I had not long been in Hertfordshire
before I saw that Bingley admired your sister,
but it was not until the dance at Netherfield
that I suspected a serious attachment.
His partiality was clear, but though she received
his attentions with pleasure,
I did not detect any symptoms
of peculiar regard.
The serenity of her countenance convinced me
that her heart was not likely to be easily touched.
Insufferable presumption!
I did not wish to believe her to be indifferent.
I believed it on impartial conviction.
Very impartial!
You've missed the two gentlemen!
They came to take their leave!
Mr. Darcy came here?
He went away directly,
but the Colonel waited for you over half an hour!
Now they are gone abroad!
I dare say we shall be able to bear
the deprivation.
As to my objections to the marriage, the
situation of your family, though objectionable,
was nothing in comparison with the total want of
propriety so frequently betrayed by your mother,
your younger sisters,
and even occasionally your father.
That will do extremely well, child.
You have delighted us long enough.
Now there will be a great marriage!
And you know, that will throw the girls
into the paths of other rich men!
My friend left Netherfield for London
on the following day.
There I pointed out to him the certain evils of
his choice of your sister as a prospective bride.
It was not difficult to convince him
of your sister's indifference to him.
I cannot blame myself for having done thus much.
For destroying all her hope of happiness?
Yes, I'm sure you do not blame yourself.
Hateful man!
There is but one part of my conduct in the affair
on which I do not reflect with satisfaction.
Really? Astonish me.
That I concealed from him
your sister's being in town.
Perhaps this concealment was beneath me.
It was done, however, for the best.
On this subject I have nothing more to say,
and no other apology to offer.
Insufferable!
- Lizzy!
- Charlotte, we will be late!
Lizzy!
I have endeavored to count the times
Lady Catherine has invited us since your arrival.
I believe it may be as many as ten invitations!
- Eleven, counting this one!
- Eleven!
There! You have indeed been favored
with peculiar condescension.
- Do you not agree, Miss Elizabeth?
- Oh... yes!
How could anybody think otherwise?
And this is your last invitation,
on this visit, at least.
It is truly a very cruel deprivation.
I hardly know how I shall bear
the loss of Lady Catherine's company.
You feel it keenly!
Yes, of course you do, my poor young cousin.
They were such fine young men,
and so particularly attached to me!
They were excessively sorry to go,
but so they always are!
The dear Colonel rallied his spirits tolerably,
but Darcy seemed to feel it most acutely.
His attachment to Rosings certainly increases.
You are very dull this evening,
Miss Elizabeth Bennet.
You have scarce spoke two words together.
Are you so out of spirits?
- No indeed, madam.
- Of course you are, to be going away yourself.
Who indeed would not be sad to be deprived
of Rosings, and indeed of the gracious...
You will write to your mother
and say you wish to stay longer.
She could certainly spare you
for another fortnight.
But my father cannot.
He wrote last week to hurry my return.
Your ladyship is very kind, but I believe
we must leave as planned on Friday.
Your father may spare you if your mother can.
Daughters are never of much consequence
to a father.
And if you will stay another month complete,
it will be in my power to take you
as far as London myself, in the Barouche box.
For I cannot bear the idea of two young women
traveling post by themselves.
It is highly improper!
I am excessively attentive to all those things.
My uncle is to send a servant for us
when we change to the post.
Your uncle! He keeps a manservant, does he?
I'm very glad you have somebody who thinks of
these things. Where will you change horses?
- At Brom...
- Bromley, of course.
Mention my name at the Bell
and they will attend you.
Your ladyship is very kind.
Indeed, we are all infinitely indebted
to your ladyship's kindly bestowed solicitude...
Yes, yes, but this is all extremely vexing!
I'm quite put out.
What are you doing? I thought the trunks
went outside before breakfast.
Lady Catherine was so severe about the only
right way to place gowns, that I couldn't sleep,
and I am determined to start afresh!
Maria, this is your trunk, these are your gowns.
You may arrange them in any way you wish.
Lady Catherine will never know!
My dear sister,
you will have much to tell your father...
Bring that one round here.
Well, cousin...
you have seen for yourself now
the happiness of our situation.
Our intimacy at Rosings is a blessing
of which few could boast.
- Indeed they could not.
- Indeed.
Now you have seen our felicity.
Perhaps you may think
your friend has made a very fortunate alliance.
Perhaps more so than...
- But on this point it will be as well to be silent.
- You are very good.
Only let me assure you that I can,
from my heart,
most cordially wish you equal felicity in marriage.
Charlotte and I have but one mind
and one way of thinking.
We seem to have been designed for each other!
How much I shall have to conceal.
You must allow me to tell you
how ardently I admire and love you.
Lizzy!
To see your faces when you looked up!
- You didn't expect we'd come to meet you.
- No, we did not.
There! ls not this nice? Cold ham and pork
and salads and every good thing!
We mean to treat you, but you must
lend us money, we spent ours. Look!
It's not pretty,
- but I thought I might as well buy it as not.
- It's vile, isn't it?
- Very ugly. What possessed you to buy it?
- There were two or three much uglier.
I shall pull it to pieces
and see if I can make it up any better.
It doesn't signify what anyone wears, for the
regiment will be at Brighton the whole summer!
Our hearts are broken!
We want papa to take us all to Brighton
for summer but he will not.
- I'm glad to hear it.
- Shouldn't you like to go to Brighton?
- I should not.
- She would.
She would love it, when she hears the news
about a certain person we all know.
- Shall we tell her?
- Yes, and watch to see if she blushes!
- You may go. We'll call if you're needed again.
- Very good, miss.
Wickham is not to marry Mary King after all!
She's been taken away by her uncle to Liverpool
and Wickham is safe!
Perhaps we should say Mary King is safe.
Was there a very strong attraction between them,
do you think'?
Not on his side! I shouldn't think
he cared three straws about her.
Who could about such a nasty freckled little thing?
Don't look at me like that, Lizzy!
I know you think as ill of her as I do.
Pass the celery, Kitty.
Aren't you glad we came to meet you?
It'll be merry on the journey home.
- Kitty, you're squashing my bandbox!
- You should have put it on the roof!
- If you didn't lollop about there'd be room for us all.
- I don't lollop, you do!
Mr. Darcy proposed! I can scarce believe it!
Not that anyone's admiring you
should be astonishing.
But he always seemed so severe,
so cold, apparently.
And yet he was in love with you all the time!
Poor Mr. Darcy.
I cannot feel so much compassion for him.
He has other feelings which will soon drive away
any regard he felt for me.
- You do not blame me for refusing him?
- Blame you? Oh, no.
But you do blame me for speaking
so warmly of Wickham?
No. How could you have known about his
vicious character? If indeed he was so very bad.
But I cannot believe Mr. Darcy would fabricate
such a dreadful slander,
involving his own sister too.
No, it must be true.
- Perhaps there has been some terrible mistake.
- No, Jane. That won't do!
You'll never be able to make them both good!
There is just enough merit between them
to make one good sort of man.
And for my part I'm inclined to believe
it's all Mr. Darcy's.
Poor Mr. Darcy.
Poor Mr. Wickham! There is such an expression
of goodness in his countenance.
Yes. I'm afraid one has all the goodness,
and the other all the appearance of it!
But, Lizzy,
I am sure when you first read that letter,
you could not have made so light of it
as you do now.
Indeed I could not.
I was very uncomfortable.
Till that moment I never knew myself.
And I had no Jane to comfort me.
Oh, how I wanted you.
There is one point on which I want your advice.
Should our general acquaintance be informed
of Wickham's true character?
Surely there can be no occasion
to expose him so cruelly.
- What is your own opinion?
- That it ought not to be attempted.
Mr. Darcy has not authorized me to make it public,
especially as regards his sister.
As for the rest, who would believe it?
The general prejudice against Mr. Darcy
is so violent, and Wickham will soon be gone.
- I believe we should say nothing at present.
- Yes, I agree.
Perhaps he is sorry now for what he has done,
and is anxious to re-establish his character.
We must not make him desperate.
Oh, Jane!
I wish I could think so well of people as you do.
Won't you speak to papa, Lizzy, about our going
to Brighton? You know he listens to your advice.
You flatter me, Lydia. In any case,
I shouldn't attempt to persuade him.
I think it's a very good thing that the regiment
should be removed from Meryton,
and that we should be removed from the regiment.
- Oh, Lizzy, how can you say such a thing?
- Very easily, ma'am.
If one company causes such havoc in our family,
what would a whole campful of soldiers do?
- A whole campful of soldiers!
- I remember when I was a girl.
I cried for two days when Colonel Miller's
regiment went away.
- I thought I should have broke my heart!
- Well, I'm sure I shall break mine.
And I!
There, there, my dears.
But your father is determined to be cruel.
I confess I am.
I'm sorry to be breaking hearts,
but I've not the smallest intention of yielding.
I shall not break my heart, papa.
The pleasures of Brighton would have no charms
for me. I should infinitely prefer a book.
- Mrs. Forster says she plans to go sea-bathing.
- I am sure I should love to go sea-bathing!
- A little sea-bathing would set me up forever!
- And yet, I am unmoved.
Well, well.
I'm glad you are come back, Lizzy.
I'm glad you are come back, Jane.
I want to go to Brighton!
You are not happy, Jane.
- It pains me to see it.
- It is just that I did...
I'm afraid I still do prefer Mr. Bingley
to any other man I've ever met,
and Lizzy, I did believe he...
Well, I was mistaken, that is all.
I am resolved to think of him no more.
There. Enough.
I shall be myself again,
as if I had never set eyes on him.
Truly, Lizzy, I promise. I shall be well.
I shall be myself again.
I shall be perfectly content.
Well, Lizzy, what do you think now
about this sad business of Jane's?
I cannot find out that she saw anything
of Bingley in London.
Well.
He is a very undeserving young man.
And I don't suppose there's the least chance
of her getting him now.
- If he should come back to Netherfield, though.
- I think there's little chance of that, mamma.
Oh, well. Just as he chooses.
No one wants him to come!
I shall always say he used my daughter
extremely ill!
If I was her, I would not have put up with it.
My comfort is, she will die of a broken heart,
and then he'll be sorry for what he's done!
So, the Collinses live quite comfortable, do they?
I only hope it will last.
And I suppose they talk about having
this house too when your father is dead?
They look on it as quite their own, I dare say?
They could hardly discuss such a subject
in front of me.
I make no doubt they talk about it constantly
when they're alone.
If they can be easy with an estate that is not
lawfully their own, so much the better.
I should be ashamed of having one
that was only entailed upon me.
Mamma, mamma! Lizzy!
Guess what! You never will, so I'll tell you.
Mrs. Forster has invited me, as her
particular friend, to go with her to Brighton.
- Colonel Forster is to take a house for us!
- Oh, Lydia! I am so happy!
- What an honor, to be singled out!
- Is it not unfair, Lizzy?
Mrs. Forster should have asked me as well.
I may not be her particular friend, but I have
just as much right to be asked as she has.
And more too, for I am two years older!
Well, I shall buy her a present, I dare say.
There's no call to be in a miff
because Mrs. Forster likes me above anyone.
Before you crow too loud, remember papa has not
given you permission to go. Nor is he like to.
Papa won't stop me. Not when I'm invited by
the Colonel to be his wife's particular companion!
I shall have to be bought new clothes. I've nothing
fit to wear and there will be balls and parties!
Of course you shall have new things! We wouldn't
see you disgraced in front of all the officers!
Ooh! All the officers!
I understand your concern, my dear,
but consider:
Lydia will never be easy until she has
exposed herself in some public place,
and here is an opportunity for her to do so, with
very little expense or inconvenience to her family.
If you were aware, Father,
of the very great disadvantage to us all,
which must arise from Lydia's unguarded and
imprudent manner, which has already arisen,
- I'm sure you would judge differently.
- Already arisen?
Has she frightened away some of your lovers?
Don't be cast down, Lizzy.
Such squeamish youths are not worth your regret.
- Oh come, Lizzy.
- Indeed you are mistaken.
I have no injuries to resent.
I speak of general, not particular evils.
Our... position as a family,
our very respectability,
is called into question by Lydia's wild behavior.
I must speak plainly. If you do not check her,
she will soon be beyond the reach of amendment.
Her character will be fixed
as the most determined flirt
that ever made herself and her family ridiculous!
You know that Kitty follows wherever Lydia leads.
Don't you see that they will be censured
and despised wherever they are known?
And that they will involve their sisters
in their disgrace.
Lizzy, come here.
Don't make yourself uneasy, my love.
Wherever you and Jane are known,
you must be respected and valued.
And you will not appear to any less advantage
for having a couple or...
I may say, three very silly sisters.
We shall have no peace at Longbourn
if Lydia does not go to Brighton.
Colonel Forster is a sensible man.
And luckily she's too poor to be an object of prey
to a fortune hunter.
Leave it now, Lizzy.
I believe all will turn out well.
We are so desolated, Colonel,
that the regiment is to leave Meryton,
but words cannot express what we feel
about your kindness to our dear Lydia.
Well, ma'am, it appears that Mrs. Forster
cannot do without her.
Look at the pair of them. Thick as thieves!
Lord knows what they find to talk about.
But anything to keep the ladies happy.
What do you say, Wickham?
I say amen to that, sir.
There's one lady I shall be very loath
to part from.
We must bear it as best we can.
You are for Brighton, I'll be touring the Lakes
with my aunt and uncle. I dare say we'll find
ample sources of consolation and delight...
- in our different ways.
- Perhaps. How did you find Rosings?
Very interesting. Colonel Fitzwilliam was there with
Mr. Darcy. Are you acquainted with the Colonel?
L...
To some respects, yes, in former years.
A very gentlemanly man.
- How did you like him?
- I liked him very much indeed.
- His manners are very different from his cousin's.
- Yes.
But I think Mr. Darcy improves
on closer acquaintance.
Indeed?
In what respect?
Has he acquired a touch of civility in his address?
For I dare not hope he is improved in essentials.
No. In essentials, I believe he is very much...
as he ever was.
Ah.
I don't mean to imply that either his mind
or his manners are changed for the better.
Rather: my knowing him better
improved my opinion of him.
I see.
Wickham. Wickham.
- Come here.
- At your service, ma'am!
Yes, 901 go'
I would not wish you back again.
- Goodbye, papa. Goodbye, mamma.
- Lydia, my dear, we shall miss you most cruelly!
I shall write every day of what I'm doing
and make you wild with envy.
- I can't help it!
- I shall not envy her a jot!
I must go. Goodbye, Jane. Goodbye, Lizzy!
If I see any eligible beaux for you,
I'll send word express!
Lord, what a laugh if I should fall
and break my head!
I wish you would!
Oh, my dear girl.
Take every opportunity of enjoying yourself!
Bye! Bye!
Never mind, Kitty. I dare say, in a year or two
you'll have got over it tolerably well.
If anyone should ask for me,
I shall be in my library, and not to be disturbed.
Hello! I can see, I can see Alicia.
Look how she has grown!
You must be so tired.
You have all grown! I think you've all grown
since we last said goodbye!
And very prettily too!
Come into the house, then.
Such a sweet, steady girl!
Well, Lizzy!
We bear you bad tidings.
Not too grievous though, I hope.
The guilt is mine. My business won't allow me
time away to visit all the Lake country.
We shall have to content ourselves
with Derbyshire.
Oh.
But Derbyshire has many beauties, has it not?
Indeed. To me Derbyshire is the best
of all counties.
You will judge for yourself whether
Chatsworth is not the equal of Blenheim.
And surely the southern counties
have nothing to compare to thewiid
Where?
At Lambton, a town of no consequence,
but to those fortunate enough to have lived in it.
I think it the dearest place in the world!
Then I shall not be happy till I have seen it.
It has one further claim on your interest:
it is but five miles from Pemberley,
and owes much of its prosperity
to that great estate.
So near?
Not that I or any of my acquaintance
enjoyed the privilege of intimacy with that family.
We moved in very different circles.
A hit! Acknowledged. Very good, sir!
- Enough, sir?
- Enough. Thank you, Baines.
- Will you come again tomorrow, sir?
- No, I have business in the North.
- I'll come back tomorrow week.
- Very good, sir. Bid you good day, sir.
Thank you, Baines. Good day.
I shall conquer this. I shall!
Elizabeth, be careful!
How could I face your father if you took a fall?
Beautiful!
- Thank you, Hannah.
- You're welcome, sir.
I should be quite happy to stay
my whole life in Derbyshire.
I'm happy to hear it. What do you say
to visiting Pemberley tomorrow?
- It's not more than a mile or two out of our way.
- Do you especially wish to see it, aunt?
I should have thought you would,
having heard so much about it.
The associations are not all unpleasant.
Wiokham passed all his youth there, you know.
We have no business there.
I should feel awkward to visit the place
without a proper invitation.
No more than Blenheim or Chatsworth.
There was no awkwardness there.
I shouldn't care for it myself, Lizzy,
if it were merely a fine house, richly furnished.
But the grounds are delightful. They have
some of the finest woods in the country.
- How far are we from Pemberley, my dear?
- Not more than five miles, sir.
- The grounds are very fine, are they not?
- As fine as you'll see anywhere, ma'am.
My oldest brother is an under-gardener there.
- Is the family here for the summer?
- No, ma'am.
Well?
Perhaps we might visit Pemberley after all.
I think we've seen woods and groves enough
to satisfy even your enthusiasm for them, Lizzy!
I confess I had no idea Pemberley
was such a great estate.
- Shall we reach the house itself before dark?
- Be patient. Wait.
There!
Stop the coach!
I think one would put up with a good deal
to be mistress of Pemberley.
The mistress of Pemberley will have to put up
with a good deal, from what I hear.
She's not likely to be anyone we know.
- How do you like the house, Lizzy?
- Very well.
I don't think I've ever seen a place
so happily situated.
I like it very well indeed.
Drive on!
A pity then, its owner should be
such a proud and disagreeable man.
Yes, a great pity.
Perhaps the beauty of the house
renders its owner a little less repulsive, Lizzy?
Yes, perhaps.
Perhaps a very little.
Well, shall we apply to the housekeeper
to see inside the place?
That's where Mrs. Darcy used to write her letters
every morning. It was her favorite room.
This is the music room.
- Charming!
- What a lovely room.
Delightful!
And there's a fine prospect from that window
down towards the lake.
- Look at this, my dear.
- It's quite magnificent!
Of all this I might have been mistress.
This piano has just come down. It's a present
from my master for Miss Georgiana.
- Your master is from home, we understand.
- Yes, but we expect him here tomorrow, sir.
He is coming with a large party of friends
and Miss Georgiana.
This portrait was painted earlier this year,
for her sixteenth birthday.
She is a very handsome young lady!
Oh, yes! The handsomest young lady
that ever was seen.
And so accomplished.
She plays and sings all day long!
Lizzy!
Look at this picture.
It reminds me very much
of someone we know!
This one, ma'am?
That young gentleman was the son
of the late Mr. Darcy's steward, Mr. Wickham.
He is gone into the army now. But he's turned out
very wild. Very wild indeed, I'm afraid.
And that's my master.
And very like him too.
It is a handsome face, but I've never seen
the original. Is it like him, Lizzy?
- Does this young lady know the master?
- Yes, a little.
And he is a handsome gentleman,
is he not, ma'am?
- Yes, very handsome.
- I'm sure I know none so handsome.
- Nor so kind.
- Indeed?
Aye, sir. I've never had a cross word from him,
and I've known him since he was four years old.
I've always observed that they
that are good-natured as children,
are good-natured when they grow up.
- His father was an excellent man.
- He was, ma'am. His son will be just like him.
The best landlord, and the best master.
Ask any of his tenants or his servants.
Some people call him proud.
I fancy that's only because he don't rattle away,
like other young men do.
Now if you will follow me, there's a finer,
larger portrait of him in the gallery upstairs.
This way, sir, if you please.
This fine account of Darcy is not quite consistent
with his behavior to poor Wickham.
- Perhaps we might have been deceived there.
- That's not likely, is it?
Ah!
Magnificent.
There!
- Would you not like to ride him, sir?
- No, take him back to the stables.
Mr. Darcy.
Miss Bennet. I...
I did not expect to see you, sir.
We understood the family were from home,
or we should never have...
I returned a day early.
Excuse me, your parents are in good health?
Yes, they are very well. I thank you, sir.
I'm glad to hear it.
How long have you been in this part
of the country?
But two days, sir.
- Where are you staying?
- Lambton Inn.
Yes, of course.
Well, I'm just arrived myself.
And your parents are in good health?
And all your sisters?
Yes, they are all in excellent health, sir.
Excuse me.
- The man himself, I presume!
- As handsome as in his portrait.
- Though perhaps a little less formally attired.
- We must leave here at once!
- Of course, if you wish.
- Oh, I wish we'd never come!
- What must he think of me?
- What did he say?
Nothing of consequence.
He enquired after my parents...
Miss Bennet. Please allow me to apologize
for not receiving you properly. Were you leaving?
- We were, sir. I think we must.
- I hope you are not displeased with Pemberley'?
No, not at all.
- Then you approve of it?
- Very much. I think there are few who would not.
Your good opinion is rarely bestowed,
and therefore more worth the earning.
Thank you.
Would you do me the honor
of introducing me to your friends?
Certainly.
Mr. and Mrs. Edward Gardiner, Mr. Darcy.
Mrs. Gardiner is my aunt, Mr. Darcy.
My sister Jane stayed at their house in Cheapside
when she was in London.
Delighted to make your acquaintance, madam, sir.
You're staying at Lambton, I hear.
Yes, sir. I grew up there as a girl.
Delightful village. I ran to Lambton as a boy
almost every day in the horse-chestnut season.
- There was one very fine tree there.
- On the green, by the smithy!
The very one.
- Mr. Gardiner, do you care for fishing?
- Indeed I do, sir, when I get the chance.
You must fish in my trout stream.
There are carp, tench and pike in the lake,
for coarse fishing.
I'll be happy to provide you with rods and tackle,
show you the best spots.
Let's walk down now.
Follow us to the lake. My man will show you.
There's a place down there
where we...
Is this the proud Darcy you told us of?
He is all ease and friendliness.
No false dignity at all!
I'm as astonished as you are. I can't imagine
what has affected this transformation.
Can you not?
- Do you...
-|...
Pray continue.
I was going to say again, sir,
how very unexpected your arrival was.
If we had known you were to be here, we should
not have dreamt of invading your privacy.
The housekeeper assured us
you would not be here until tomorrow.
Do not make yourself uneasy.
I had planned it so myself,
but I found I had business with my steward.
I rode on ahead of the rest of the party.
They will join me tomorrow.
And among them are those who claim
an acquaintance with you.
It's Mr. Bingley and his sisters.
Oh.
There is the other person in the party
who more particularly wishes to know you.
Will you allow me to...
Do I ask too much to introduce my sister to you,
during your stay at Lambton?
I should be very happy to make her acquaintance.
Thank you.
I hope we shall meet again very soon.
Good day, Mr. Gardiner. Mrs. Gardiner.
Good day, Miss Bennet.